Guide to the Cornell Migrant Program records, [ca. 1953-2005]
Cornell Migrant Program records, [ca. 1953-2005]
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell Migrant Program records, [ca. 1953-2005].
23-13-3160
43.7 cubic feet.
Photographs, slides, videos, correspondence, publications, reports.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
In 1979 the program was transferred to the Department of Human Development and Family Studies and renamed the Cornell Migrant Program. Engman became the director and Kay Embrey became the Wayne County office director in 1980. Kathy (Fox) Castania was hired in 1981 and she and Embrey founded the Wayne Action for Racial Equality. For the first years of the program all funding was provided by the College of Agriculture and Cornell Cooperative Extension. By the mid 1970's, grant money was being raised to expand programs. As of 1994, the financial support was divided between the College of Human Ecology, the College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, Cornell Cooperative Extension and grant money.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
In 1979 the program was transferred to the Department of Human Development and Family Studies and renamed the Cornell Migrant Program. Engman became the director and Kay Embrey became the Wayne County office director in 1980. Kathy (Fox) Castania was hired in 1981 and she and Embrey founded the Wayne Action for Racial Equality. For the first years of the program all funding was provided by the College of Agriculture and Cornell Cooperative Extension. By the mid 1970's, grant money was being raised to expand programs. As of 1994, the financial support was divided between the College of Human Ecology, the College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, Cornell Cooperative Extension and grant money.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, reports, manuals, publications, minutes of meetings, newsletters, and photographs of various programs and projects concerning migrant workers and their families and farm labor laws and regulations.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Engman, Herbert J.; Johnson, Stephen P.; Embrey, Kay.; Dik, David W.; Hanson, Karen Tobin.; Castania, Kathy Fox.; Agricultural Manpower Project.; Wayne County Special Migrant Project (N.Y.); Wayne Action for Racial Equality.; Rural Economic and Social Development Program.; New York State College of Human Ecology. Dept. of Human Development and Family Studies.; New York State College of Human Ecology.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.; Cornell Cooperative Extension.
Subjects:
Migrant labor--United States.; Labor camps--New York (State).; Children of migrant laborers--Education.; Agricultural laborers--New York (State).; Labor laws and legislation--United States.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See also: Cornell Migrant Program campus collection, #23-13-3582, http://resolver.library.cornell.edu/cgi-bin/EADresolver?id=RMA03582.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Formation of Program through 1970-1989
Series II. General Programs 1970-2004
Series III. Oral History & Literacy Programs
Series IV. Migrant Farmworker Housing
Series V. Discrimination, Cultural Groups & Multi-Cultural Arts Project
Series VI. Health
Series VII. Pesticides & Occupational Health
Series VIII. Services
Series IX. Education & Children
Series X. Labor Management Programs
Series XI. Agricultural Careers Development Project
Series XII. Labor Management - Cornell
Series XIII. Labor Management - California
Series XIV. Farm Labor Laws and Regulations
Series XV. Government Bodies & Groups
Series XVI. Immigration
Series XVII. WARE
Series XVIII. Migrant Education Clippings & News/Views
Series XIX. News/Views 1992-2000
Series XX. Farm Labor Research (by person's name)
Series XXI. Cornell Extension Programs Related to Labor
Series XXII. Immigration Policy & Reports
Series XXIII. Immigration Coalition & New York Immigration Issues
Series XXIV. Alcohol & Substance Abuse
Series XXV. Historical Papers & Cornell Traveling Museum Exhibit: "Coming Up on the Season"
Series XXVI. Farm Labor Topics - N.Y. & Other States
Series XXVII. Health & Field Sanitation II
Series XXVIII. Ag. Work Force PWT & Immigrants in Rural Communities
Series XXIX. Alton Office - Kay Embrey, 1990-2005
Series XXX. Labor Management - California
Series XXXI. Farmworker Rights in New York & Other States
Series XXXII. Agencies & Services in Wayne County & New York State
Series XXXIII. Communications
Series XXXIV. Photographs and Slides
Series XXXV. Literacy
Series XXXVI. Action/Cooperative Communication Between Home & School
Series XXXVII. Substance Abuse
Series XXXVIII. Videos/Audiotapes
Series XXXIX. Cornell Migrant Program and Cornell
Series XL. Albany Day Marches/Press
Series XLI. Coursework
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Formation of Program through 1970-1989
  - L. Watson letter to Dean Palm, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Orange County Cornell Cooperative Extension Migrant Report, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Migrant labor in Wayne County report by Gottfried, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Needs of Migrant Workers - LaMont, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3A)
  - Godfrey youth program report, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Housing lawsuit - Bossard/Dik, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Wayne labor camps controversy, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Agriculture Manpower project (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Agriculture Policy Accountability Project, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Social responsibility in Wayne and Chenango counties, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Observation agricultural youth - Godfrey, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Manpower training programs (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Wayne Housing Opportunities, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Agriculture Manpower conference for agents, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Economic independence - Tobin, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Macon youth program report, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Spalding reports, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Wayne County Manpower program, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - University senate, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Realizing our Objectives - Tobin, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Tobin progress reports (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Wayne County agriculture Manpower program - Dik (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Committee on migrant labor (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - On failing farmworkers, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Special migrant project, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Court action for migrants - Migrant Legal Action Program, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence - special migrant project, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - RIF, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Housing/CASH, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Pesticide education - Youth, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Nutrition aides, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Community youth investigation project, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - S. Johnson presentations (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Summer programs, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Special migrant project board, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Farmworker Rights Handbook - Migrant Assistance Project CPFT, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Sodus summer education highlights, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Think Piece" on special migrant projects, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Migrant education conference - David Dik, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Sodus summer programs, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Sodus Summer Programs, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - EFNEP - Youth, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Low income youth - Ad hoc committee, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Day haul workers, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Plans of work - Johnson and Engman, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Community uninvolved youth project, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Garden and Worm Project - Uninvolved youth, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Special migrant project evaluation- Johnson, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Special migrant projects and programs, 1974, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Summer enrichment program, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Eastern farmworkers, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Eastern farmworkers in Wayne County and Binghamton, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Child care need - Wayne County - Delano, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Reports to Wayne County Cooperative Extension Board, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Cornell Cooperative Extension and unionization, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Wayne County youth home project, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Wayne County youth project, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - 1-57 Wayne County Migrant Youth Project Sodus and N. Rose-Wolcott, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - 1-58 Wayne County agency survey, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Rural economic and social development programs - Adv. Committee, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Migrant education and rural housing programs - Morrison, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Wayne County rural development - Morrison, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Morrison resignation, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Numbers of migrant farmworkers in New York State, 1968, 1973, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Fifteen Thousand Challenges - Wayne CAP, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - People of Wayne County 1900-1962, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Earnings of migrant farmworkers in Wayne County New York - Geneseo, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Wayne County farmworkers, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Economic Analysis - Regional and Wayne County, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Labor waste in New York: Rural exploitation and migratory farmworkers-Friedland, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Response to marginality: Case of migrant farmworkers - Nelkin, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Aspects of migrant labor system - Nelkin, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - On the Season - D. Nelkin, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Migrant in the 1970's: Challenge of Powerlessness - Daniel (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Agriculture Labor Stats- Northeast United States - Penn State, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - The Migrant Papers - Harrison, 1972 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Impact of federal programs on migrant farmworkers and southern farmworkers, 1973 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Migrant child census - New York State, 1974-1978 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Working with migrants - R. Coles, 1976 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Government Committee on Migrant and Rural Poor, 1977 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Reports on migrant farmworkers and southern farmworkers - New York State, 1978 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Migrant farmworkers in Western New York- Young, Johnson, et-al, 1978 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Migrant farmworkers in New York State- Dudley and Perez, 1980 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Migrant farmworkers In Western New York: Changes 1951-1978- Young and John, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Wayne County census and economic development studies, 1969-1976 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Migratory Labor in New York State - student paper, 1978 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Economic profile - Wayne County, 1976 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Dynamics of migratory settlement in Wayne County -Hughes, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Cohn Camp closing, 1971 (Box 47, Folder 14)
- Series II. General Programs 1970-2004
  - Migrants in western New York: Needs and agencies, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cornell Migrant Program progress report - Engman, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cornell Migrant Program 1982 and the Future - Engman (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Re-organization of Wayne County program, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cornell Migrant Program move to the Dept. of Human Development and Family Studies - Ziegler, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Programs overviews, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Delores Franklin visit - SED, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Programs and priorities, 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Wayne County Advisory Board- minutes, 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Wayne County Advisory Board- minutes, 1985-1991 (Box 2, Folder 9A)
  - Migrant Program Reports- Wayne County, 1981-1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Reports to Wayne County Cooperative Extension Board, 1980-1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Embrey plan of work, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Embrey- Annual report of faculty activities, 1981-1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence in and out, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Program needs of migratory farmworkers in Wayne County, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Labor regs meeting, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Farm Net Program correspondence, 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Youth tractor driving and maintenance course - Summer, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Summer and Fall programs, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Literacy proposal, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - New York food policy white paper - Engman testimony, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 2-22 Migrant farmworkers slide show - Engman (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 2-23 Summer and Fall programs, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Program flyers, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Haitian culture workshop, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Tractor driving class photos (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Programs in Wayne County report, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Literacy program, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Summer and Fall programs, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Literacy program, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - The Bucket Performance, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Summer and Fall programs, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - 2-33 Cornell Migrant Program flyer, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Literacy classes, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Cornell Migrant Program staff trip, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Smith Labor Camp - news article, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Summer and fall programs, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Literacy program, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Literacy program, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Summer Fall programs, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Summer Fall programs, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Kathy reports (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - EFNEP - Wayne County migrant project, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Wayne County performing arts, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Wayne County agencies - Sharing meeting, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Wayne County Migrant agencies Sharing Day, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Wayne County Migrant agencies- sharing meeting, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Migrant agencies - Ontario County, Hudson Valley, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Wayne County migrant agencies - Sharing Day, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Wayne County migrant agencies - Sharing Day, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Wayne County migrant agencies - Sharing Day, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Wayne County agencies- Sharing meeting, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - St. Rita's Church - Witness with the Poor, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Changing migrant scene - Kay's conference notebook, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Cornell Migrant Program Conference - Migrant Farmworkers in New York Past, Present and Future, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Change for migrant farmworkers - cancelled conference, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Change for Migrant Farmworkers Conference, 1986-11 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Change for Migrant Farmworkers II - Conference, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Migrant/Racism Conference Planning, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Cornell Migrant Program Conference - Institutional Racism, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Cornell Migrant Program, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Migrant Farmworkers In America: Analysis of Social Policy - Roberts, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Presence and Absence of Farmworkers Families - Roberts, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Kevin Rivers - College admission, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Proposal: Wayne Youth training program, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Rochester Farmworkers' Rights Organization, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Savanah Potato Harvest, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Opinion - Seventh national conference on migrant education - Dik, 1974 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Hearings on migrant education guidelines, 1977 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - CRIC/CRESS, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Teacher training materials "Harvesting the Harvester", 1985 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Tapes - "Harvesting the Harvesters" - hosted by Ken and Nan Lawless (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Educating undocumented children, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Preventing Child Abuse in the Harvest: A Handbook for Migrant Educators, 1985 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - New York State Education Dept. Adolescent Program Review, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - New York State Education Dept. Migrant Education Program Report, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Migrant Student Record Transfer System (MSRTS) recommendations, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Secondary youth planner and resources - Credit exchange, 1993 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Credit accrual for secondary youth - Credit exchange, 1994 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Curriculum and migrant students, 1994 (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - National Forum - Migrant Children and Youth (IMEC), 1997 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Migrant Children:Education and Improve Exchange of Info, 1999 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Opening Closed Doors - Castania thesis, 1993 (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Even Start:Home Literacy - Pat Ward (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - Interstate Migrant Education Council (Box 44, Folder 24)
  - Geneseo Migrant Center (Box 44, Folder 25)
  - Pass Center - Geneseo, 2004 (Box 44, Folder 26)
  - School attendance - Immigrant students (Box 44, Folder 27)
  - Migrant education outreach program (Box 44, Folder 28)
  - New York State Parent Advisory Council (Box 44, Folder 29)
  - New York State Migrant Education Conference, 1997-2000 (Box 44, Folder 30)
  - New York State Migrant Education Conference, 2001-2004 (Box 44, Folder 31)
  - Consortium directories (Box 44, Folder 32)
  - College tuition for migrant students, 1988 (Box 44, Folder 33)
  - Center for Immigrant Students (Box 44, Folder 34)
  - High School Equivalency Program (HEP) and the College Assistance Migrant Program (CAMP), 2003 (Box 44, Folder 35)
  - Federal stats - Summary for education, 2002 (Box 44, Folder 36)
- Series III. Oral History and Literacy Programs
  - Oral history photos (Box 3)
  - Oral history tapes (Box 3)
  - Oral history slides (Box 3)
  - Final publication: oral histories (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Oral history- original publication (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Fruit Industry in Wayne County 1823-1984 - Wayne Historical Society, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Open house for publication (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Hoffman Foundation Award, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Oral histories collected by migrant education (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 4-H oral history projects, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Slide show script (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 4-H objectives (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Oral history project timeline, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 4-H oral history project - Faso's notes (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Oral histories by Jane Spring, Niagara County, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - More Than One Journey - C. Jackson, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - New York Folklore: Migrant workers, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Literacy program reports (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Literacy program- news coverage (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Literacy coalition (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - VISTA/ literacy volunteer - Geneseo (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Literacy project overviews (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Letters to tutors (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Literacy programs - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Literacy program - Grants (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Penfield students as tutors (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Tutor newsletter, 1982,1983,1984 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Tutor newsletter, 1985,1986,1987 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Series IV. Migrant Farmworker Housing
  - Housing for migrant farmworkers - Cornell Migrant Program, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Migrant housing in New York State: Construction guidelines, 1970/before (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Housing for migrant farmworkers - USDA, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Housing needs - Wayne County Planning Board, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - To House the Migrant - New York State, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Migrant shelter - A housing dilemma Finger Lakes region planning board, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - New York State Rural Housing Coalition, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - New York State sanitary code for migrant labor camps, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - United States Department of Labor housing regulations, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - OSHA labor camp regulations, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Hired farmworker housing - United States Department of Agriculture, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - The committee report: Farmworker housing, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - FMHA farmworker loans, 1980-1987 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Homes of the Brave: Report on migrant farmworkers housing, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Evictions from labor camps - Embrey, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Wayne County housing, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Chi's comparison of housing, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Hope Village Story, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Farm labor housing in New York State - RNYFO, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Migratory labor housing - Michigan, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Rensselaerville Institute - Modular housing, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Migrant farmworkers housing in Niagara County - Frombgen, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Ontario labor camp hearing, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Letter to editor - Embrey, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Huron Labor Camp hearing, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Williamson Labor Camp, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Geneva Labor Camp hearing, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Rural Opportunities Inc. letter concerning hearing - Mitchell, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Employer assisted housing - LaQuatra, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - FmHA tour - Wayne County, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Harvest Court apartment - Rural Opportunities Inc., 1989 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - DeMay Camp open house, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Hanson Farms open house, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Out of the Stream: Cultural sensitivity in Housing Bell, Pennsylvania, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Orange County Health Department, 1983-1993 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Access to labor camps, 1991,1993 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Employee Housing: Guide for Farm Employers - Embrey, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Recommends for housing demonstration programs in New York State Rural Opportunities Inc., 1993 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Building Blocks - Rural Opportunities Inc. newsletter, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - RHAC and Harvest Court - Rural Opportunities Inc., 1991-1996 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - New York State revolving loan fund, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - New York Times Housing article, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Newfane Town ordinance, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Farmworker housing in New York State - Rural Opportunities Inc., 2000 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Wayne County migrant camps, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - New York State migrant camp, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Wayne County camp list, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Wayne County camp list, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Wayne County camp list, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Wayne County camp list, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Wayne County camp list, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Wayne County camp list, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Wayne County camp list, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Wayne County camp list, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Wayne County camp list, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Wayne County camp list, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Wayne County camp list, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Wayne County camp list, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Wayne County camp list, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Wayne County camp list, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Camp list - Surrounding counties (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Camp list - Orange County, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Camp list - Orleans and Orange Counties, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Migrant camp report by county, 1980, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Revolving loan fund, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Housing code revisions, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - MOU - New York Department of Labor and Department of Housing on housing inspections, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 67)
- Series V. Discrimination, Cultural Groups and Multi-Cultural Arts Project
  - After the Harvest: Plight of Older Farmworkers, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Women's equity project - RNYFO, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Valiant migrant women - Hintz, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)